Pratik Bhandari

3381 E Ruby Hill Dr, Pleasanton, CA, 94539

Phone: (970) 286-8296 Email: pratik.codes@gmail.com

Summary

I am a Full Stack Javascript developer with development experience with the MEAN stack and current focus on React and Flux. I code full stack apps, web and mobile, and enjoy solving problems using Javascript. I am always excited to learn new and efficient technologies and integrating new features with them in my projects.

Projects

Inter Language Chat

9Gag clone — July 2016

Created a chat room app where people can chat with other people who speak different languages but in your own language.

Accomplishments

- User Google Translate API to detect input language and translate to each user's preferred language.
- Used NodeJs and ExpressJs for the backend
- Used Socket.io for real time messaging.
- Used ReactJs for front end.
- Used Heroku to deploy..

Meme hub

9Gag clone — June 2016

Created a full stack app with full CRUD functionality in 10 days break. It is basically an image sharing app where you can post funny pictures and see other users post. You can also like, dislike and comment on other people's post.

Accomplishments

- Used the full MEAN stack:
 - NodeJs and ExpressJs for the backend
 - MongoDB for database
 - AngularJs and HTML, CSS for the frontend.
- Fully implemented user authentication.
- Used Amazon AWS S3 services to store static images.

Reflecti

Social Media — June 2016

Reflecti is a social media where you can view vines from the public vine api and capture your emotions through a camera and display it as reactions for other people to see. It is an alternative approach to display your actual reactions in contrast to classic likes and comments.

Accomplishments

- Learned and finished the iOS version of the app using React Native and Flux.
- Collaborated with 3 other teammates who worked on different aspects of the project.

Skills

- Web Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Frontend: jQuery, AngularJs, Ionic, React, React Native, Flux
- Backend: Node, Express, Socket.io, Mongoose
- Database: MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB
- Testing and task runners: Gulp, Mocha, Chai, Karma, Webpack
- Other languages: C++

Education

Southeast Missouri State University

Computer Science — 2011 - 2015

Experience

Coding House

Full stack Javascript — April 2016 - July 2016

Created full stack javascript web applications with jQuery, React, the MEAN stack and AWS services. Above listed are projects are which I worked on.

Coding House

Teaching Assistant — July 2016 - August 2016

Created tutorials on the class material about full stack javascript app development. Helped and mentored new students in class and assisted the instructor with their teaching materials.